NICHOLAS SEIDL

Machine Learning Engineer

I have experience working on various **computer vision, natural language processing,** and **machine learning** projects. I'm currently at Apple in Intelligent System Experience - System Intelligence Machine Learning working on Generative AI. I built a **real-time object detector (YOLO)** for Wayfair in Summer 2019. In Spring 2019, I worked on **robustness analysis** (RA) of Apple's Neural Face Detector. In Spring + Summer 2018, I built two **web services** at Apple: one for **content analysis and retrieval** and one for **hosted image comparisons and history**.

Contact

nicholasseidl@gmail.com (650)-739-6674



nseidl.io



/in/nicholaskseidl



github.com/nseidl

Languages

Python, Java, Javascript, C, C++

Software

GenAl, LLMs, VQA, RLHF, CLIP, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas, NumPy, CoreML, TensorRT, TFLite, Flask, React, Postgres, AWS, EC2, S3, Docker, Airflow, Kubernetes

Courses

Algorithms and Data Structures Artificial Intelligence Linear Algebra Distributed Systems ML and Data Mining Object Oriented Design Computer Systems Programming Languages Probability and Statistics

Interests

Formula 1, Chess, Pool, <u>Photography</u>, Basketball, Hiking

Experience

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

ISE SIML - Machine Learning Engineer

February 2020 - Present

• Email me for the most up-to-date version of my resume

Wayfair LLC

Boston, MA

Data Science - Computer Vision Engineer

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Implemented YOLO(v3) neural network for live on-device object detection
- Optimized with quantization, CUDA, cuDNN, TensorRT, and Tensor Cores
- Achieved 80x speedup in inference time and up to 4x smaller model sizes

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

C&P CVML - Machine Learning Engineer

Jan. 2019 - June 2019

- Analyzed failures of face detector to target aggressors and guide development
- Designed and automated RA pipeline: inference → detection evaluation → RA
- Managed data collection, selection, and annotation (guidelines, spec, and quality)

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

IMG QE - Full Stack Software Engineer

Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Content Collection: audio/image/video/stream analysis and retrieval (Tornado)
 - Integrated blob (Amazon S3) and metadata (Postgres) stores to serve content
 - Extracted attributes from audio, image, video, and stream content (Swift)
- Image Comparisons: image comparison web service with history (Flask)
 - Rewrote backend so different comparison algorithms can easily be added

Education

Northeastern University

Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2019 GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

Khoury College of Computer Sciences